proxyvote.com 2017-06-06

# Privacy Statement | Broadridge

Broadridge believes that privacy is important to the success and use of the Internet. This Statement describes the practices that Broadridge will follow with respect to the personal information it collects from users of www.broadridge.com and other Broadridge websites, mobile applications, or hosted websites that link to this Privacy Statement.

**What is personal information?**

“Personal information” is information that can be used to identify or contact you. Personal information includes your name, address, e-mail address, and phone number, as well as information you provide us about your interests and preferences.

In some cases, we operate or host websites owned by our clients, including banks, brokers, mutual funds and corporations or other business entities (the “Business Owner” of the website). On these hosted sites, we may also collect sensitive personal information that you provide, which for some services may include your account number and Social Security number, as well as information you provide when you access your account online or conduct transactions. All personal information and sensitive personal information collected via these hosted sites is considered “Confidential Information.”

**How do we collect, use, and disclose personal information?**

On Broadridge websites we collect personal information that you provide so that we may provide you or our clients with, or contact you about, products, services and information, to enhance your site visit or follow up with you after your visit.

If you provide personal information to us for our own use, we may use it to provide the products, services or information that you have requested and we may share it with our affiliates. We may also use your personal information for other internal business purposes, such as market research and legal compliance.

If you provide personal information or sensitive personal information to us via a hosted site, we treat that information as confidential and we only use it to perform the services requested by you or the Business Owner of the site. We may share your information with the Business Owner of the site, and also provide the Business Owner with information on your use of the website. If you have any questions regarding the Business Owner’s use of your personal information, please contact the Business Owner directly. Broadridge may use aggregate information or statistics about the use of its sites and the products and services used through its sites, but these statistics would not include personal information.

We may share any personal information, even Confidential Information, with our vendors and other third parties who perform services for us, but we forbid these companies from using your personal information for their own purposes.

Please note that we may always disclose any information as required by law, when necessary for health or safety purposes, or when needed to protect our legal rights, including to law enforcement agencies and courts in the United States and other countries where we operate in accordance with applicable laws. For example, we may disclose information about you in response to a subpoena. We may also disclose information about you in connection with the transfer of assets of our business.

Finally, if you are located outside the United States, your personal information will be maintained by us in the U.S. We may transfer your personal information to countries outside your location or the U.S. However, we assure adequate protection for your personal information in compliance with all applicable laws.

**Cookies and Other Data Collection Technologies**

When you visit our website or use our mobile applications, we may collect certain information by automated means, using technologies such as cookies, pixel tags, browser analysis tools, server logs and web beacons. We do not, however, use tracking or cookie technology on pages of our websites that provide notice and access hosting services to public companies.

When you visit our website, we place cookies on your computer. Cookies are small text files that websites send to your computer or other Internet-connected device to uniquely identify your browser or to store information or settings in your browser. Cookies allow us to recognize you when you return. They also help us provide a customized experience and enable us to detect certain kinds of fraud. In many cases, you can manage cookie preferences and opt-out of having cookies and other data collection technologies used by adjusting the settings on your browser. All browsers are different, so visit the “help” section of your browser to learn about the privacy settings that may be available.   

We may also use Flash Cookies (also known as Local Stored Objects) and similar technologies to personalize and enhance your online experience _._ The Adobe Flash Player is an application that allows rapid development of dynamic content, such as video clips and animation. We use Flash cookies for security purposes and to help remember settings and preferences. We do not use Flash cookies or similar technologies for behavioral or interest-based advertising purposes. To manage Flash cookies, please see Adobe’s website at <http://kb2.adobe.com/cps/526/52697ee8.html> or visit [www.adobe.com](http://www.adobe.com/). 

In connection with Broadridge marketing efforts, we may use pixel tags and web beacons.  Pixel tags and web beacons are tiny graphic images placed on website pages or in our emails that allow us to determine whether you have performed a specific action. When you access these pages or open or click an email, the pixel tags and web beacons generate a notice of that action. These tools allow us to measure response to our communications and improve our web pages and promotions. Information collected using these technologies in our e-mails may be associated with the recipient’s e-mail address.

We collect many different types of information from cookies and other technologies. For example, we may collect information from the device you use to access our website, your 

operating system type, browser type, domain, and other system settings, as well as the language your system uses and the country and time zone where your device is located. Our server logs also record the IP address assigned to the device you use to connect to the Internet. An IP address is a unique number that devices use to identify and communicate with each other on the Internet. We may also collect information about the website you were visiting before you came to Broadridge and the website you visit after you leave our site. 

In many cases, the information we collect using cookies and other tools is only used in a non-identifiable way, without any reference to Personal Information. For example, we use information we collect about all website users to optimize our websites and to understand website traffic patterns. In some cases, we do associate the information we collect using cookies and other technology with your Personal Information. This Privacy Statement applies to the information when we associate it with your Personal Information.

**Browser Tracking Information**

On some of our sites, such as [www.broadridge.com](http://www.broadridge.com/) and Advanced Annual Meeting Solutions’ websites (the Shareholder Forum and Virtual Shareholder Meeting, which may be customized for the Business Owner), and mobile applications Broadridge directly or through third parties uses Google Analytics, Adobe Analytics, and/or Demandbase, Inc.’s (“Demandbase’s”) web analytics to provide Broadridge or its clients with information about the use of Broadridge’s websites. 

Google Analytics is a web analytics tool that helps website owners understand how visitors engage with their website. Using Google Analytics we can view a variety of reports about how visitors interact with our website so that we can improve it. This tool is provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses “cookies”, which are text files placed on your computer, to help our website analyze how users use our site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of our website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of our website, compiling reports on website activity and providing other services relating to our website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. Google may combine this information with other data held by Google pursuant to Google’s privacy policy available on Google’s website. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser; however, please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of our website. By using the Broadridge websites, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above. For information on how Google Analytics uses data please visit “How Google uses data when you use our partners’ sites or apps”, located at [www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/).

Broadridge also uses web analytics tools provided by Adobe. These tools provide similar reporting and analytics functions. To learn more about privacy and the Abode analytics products and to exercise your privacy choices with Adobe, please visit the Adobe Privacy Center located at <http://www.adobe.com/privacy/marketing-cloud.html>.

Broadridge provides Demandbase with the IP addresses recorded by Broadridge’s server logs of visitors to Broadridge’s sites. Demandbase’s web analytics then identify information about visitors to Broadridge’s sites, including, without limitation, industry, size, location and revenue, based on Demandbase’s extensive database of company IP addresses. By using the Broadridge websites, you consent to the processing of your IP address and data about you by Demandbase in the foregoing manner.

Although our websites currently do not have a mechanism to recognize the various web browser Do Not Track signals, we do offer individuals choices to manage their cookie preferences as described above. To learn more about browser tracking signals and Do Not Track please visit <http://www.allaboutdnt.org/>

**Social Media Interactions and Interest-based Ads** ****

Our websites may enable you to interact with us and others via social media platforms, such as Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn and Instagram. While we respect each social media platform’s privacy policies, we may collect personal information about you and your friends if you choose to use these tools.

We may display interest-based ads to you when you are using platforms such as Facebook and Google. These platforms allow us to personalize the ads that we display to you. We do not share any of your personal information with these platforms, although we may convert your email address into a unique number which can be matched by the platform with its user to allow delivery of the advertising. Although we do not provide any personal information to these platforms, they may gain insights about individuals who respond to the ads we display.

**Mobile Applications**

We may offer mobile applications that allow you to access your account, interact with us online and receive other information via your smartphone. All personal information collected by Broadridge via our mobile applications is protected by the terms of this Privacy Statement.   

When you download our mobile applications, you may choose to allow us to obtain your precise location from your mobile device. We use this information to deliver personalized content to you and for our internal analytics purposes.

We may also offer automatic (or “push”) notifications. We will provide push notifications only to those individual who opt-in to receive such notifications from Broadridge. You do not have to provide location information to Broadridge or enable push notifications to use any of our mobile apps. If you have questions about location and notification privacy, please contact your mobile service provider or the manufacturer of your device to learn how to adjust your settings.

**Do we collect your information for marketing communications?**

Broadridge is a business to business service provider and does not market its services to individual consumers. However, Broadridge does provide certain information by subscription and uses an opt-in format for choosing future e-mail communications in specified subject areas. These e-mail communications contain links to unsubscribe from future e-mail communications. Broadridge also may use the personal information you provide on Broadridge websites to contact you to respond to your inquiries or to contact your business about information relating to Broadridge’s or its affiliate’s products and services from time to time. Please email us at [info@broadridge.com](mailto:info@broadridge.com) if you do not want your information used for further marketing contact. Broadridge does not send Broadridge marketing communications to individuals who provide us with personal information via a hosted website for a Business Owner.

**How can you correct, access, and update your information?**

You may view and edit the personal information you have provided on any of our websites by contacting us using the link provided on such website. Our customer support department can also reasonably assist you with other requests related to information about you that may be maintained by us. Please send requests to [privacy@broadridge.com](mailto:privacy@broadridge.com).

**How do we protect your information?**

We take reasonable steps to help prevent the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. For example, we have implemented physical, logical, and administrative procedures to protect and secure the information we process and maintain. We also use encryption and firewall technologies to protect sensitive information during online transmissions.

**How can you help protect your information?**

If you have registered at a Broadridge website or a hosted website, we recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. We will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or in an unsolicited e-mail. Also remember to sign out of the registered site and close your browser window when you have finished your work. This is to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if others have access to your computer.

**Can we change this Privacy Statement?**

From time to time, we may want to use personal information in ways that are not anticipated by this Privacy Statement. If we make a material change to this Statement or in how Broadridge will use your personal information, we will notify you either by posting and highlighting the policy changes before they take effect or by directly sending you a notification. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Statement to learn how Broadridge is protecting your information.

**International Data Transfers**

Broadridge and certain affiliates process personal information. Broadridge is committed to handling such personal information in accordance with applicable laws. Personal information transfers from the European Economic Area are authorized by approved model contracts or other appropriate means. Broadridge has historically participated in the U.S.-E.U. and U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Privacy Programs. Although the Safe Harbor framework is no longer a valid basis for the transfer of EU Personal Information, Broadridge continues to comply with the Safe Harbor Principles internally as a demonstration of our commitment to the protection of personal information.

**Privacy Protection Policy for Social Security Numbers**

Broadridge may collect Social Security numbers in the ordinary course of certain of its businesses. Broadridge has implemented reasonable technical, physical and administrative safeguards to help protect the Social Security numbers from unlawful use and unauthorized disclosure. All Broadridge associates and service providers are required to follow these established procedures. 

In particular:

  * Access to Social Security numbers is limited to those associates and service providers who have a need to access the information to perform tasks for Broadridge
  * Social Security numbers are only disclosed to third parties in accordance with Broadridge’s established policies. Broadridge will only disclose Social Security numbers to those service providers, auditors, advisors, and/or successors in interest who are legally or contractually obligated to protect them or as required or permitted by law

**Other sites**

Broadridge sites may contain links to other sites, including those of our business partners. While we seek to link only to sites that share our high standards and respect for privacy, we are not responsible for the privacy practices employed by other sites.

**Broadridge Corporate Issuer Solutions Information Security Program**

Broadridge Corporate Issuer Solutions, a registered transfer agent, maintains an information security program to address the risk that customer information acquired in the course of its business is disclosed inadvertently without authorization, misused, altered, destroyed, or otherwise compromised. As part of this information security program, Corporate Issuer Solutions has designed and implemented safeguards to prevent such disclosure, misuse, alteration, destruction, or compromise and has implemented appropriate measures to oversee its service providers’ compliance with the program. Corporate Issuer Solutions also has adopted protocols for the proper disposal of any consumer report information acquired in the course of its business.

Corporate Issuer Solutions has implemented numerous physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to prevent the unauthorized sharing of personal shareholder information, including the limiting of information to necessary employees and the encryption of sensitive website transmissions using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protection. Corporate Issuer Solutions may maintain some or all of the following personal information with respect to individual shareholders:

  * Shareholder name and address(es)
  * Shareholder taxpayer identification number
  * Information related to the shareholder’s share ownership, history, and/or dividends
  * In some cases, shareholder telephone numbers and/or e-mail addresses
  * In some cases, shareholder bank or brokerage account information
  * In some case, information from tax-related documents that is required to process tax reports and statements, stock transfers, and other securities transactions

Corporate Issuer Solutions maintains its records of securities and shareholders as an agent for the issuer of the security, and, accordingly, will provide the above-referenced information to the issuer or its designees. Corporate Issuer Solutions does not provide the aforementioned information about current or former shareholders to any third party except to provide the services or as permitted by law. Corporate Issuer Solutions will provide personal information:

  * When necessary to effect, administer, or enforce a transaction requested by the shareholder
  * When the shareholder requests or authorizes that the information be shared
  * When the disclosure is necessary to prevent fraud
  * When the disclosure is necessary for Corporate Issuer Solutions to perform its duties
  * When providing information necessary for third parties to perform services on behalf of Corporate Issuer Solutions
  * When the disclosure is required by law.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should contact us at [privacy@broadridge.com](mailto:privacy@broadridge.com).

_This Privacy Statement was last updated February 1, 2017._
